CURRICULUM VITAE

ABOUT ME

As a test development engineer with a Master of Science in electrical and information technology, my broad career has given me extensive insights into various specialist areas. I discovered my passion for software development and continuously expanded my knowledge and skills by acquiring various certificates and through self-study. Now I am faced with the exciting challenge of taking the important step into the field of web and app development. My goal is to support my future employer with my in-depth expertise and to take on new challenges every day in order to further develop my skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Since 09/2023

SenDev GmbH | Mini job

Software Engineer

Development PickATask:

Development of a to-do list app based on a points and reward system using .net MAUI and Blazor

Development iOSScan:

Development of a document scanning tool for integration into a .net MAUI project

Since 04/2022

Elmos Semiconductor SE | Dortmund

Test Development Engineer

Development of test hardware:

Layout and design of the required circuit for testing the IC

Commissioning and verification of the DUT board (Device Under test) on the T2000 IPSE test machine

Development of test software:

Hardware-related programming on T2000 IPSE test machine to verify the developed test hardware

Generation of automated scripts for efficient implementation of test software Creating specific patterns to configure the hardware to be tested

11/2021 - 04/2022

PSW automotive Engineering GmbH | Gaimersheim

Function Owner ADAS

Active safety:

Execution and evaluation of test cases with CANoe/CAPL based on real measured values in the PreCrash area

Processing of specifications in Doors to check the required parameters in the PreCrash area

Verification of the parameters in real time under real conditions in the vehicle

Tooling for responsible functions:

Programming scripts to create test reports based on measured values Use of various plugins to graphically display the measured values using an HTML plot

01/2019 - 04/2020

Fraunhofer IML | Dortmund

Working Student

- Hardware development of smart devices for proof-of-concept
- Hardware-related programming (Raspberry Pi)
- Creation of layout and circuitry

09/2016 - 04/2017

WILO SE | Dortmund

Working Student

05/2015 – 09/2015 Siemens AG | Mülheim a.d. Ruhr

Operating Experience

EDUCATION

10/2017 – 09/2020 "Technische Universität Dortmund" | Dortmund

Major: Electrical Engineering and Information Technology | Master of Science (2,3)

Thesis: Compilation of physically motivated propagation models for indoor radio propagation

Advisor: Dr. Ing. Wolfgang Endemann

04/2017 – 09/2017 Tohoku University | Sendai (Japan)

Major: Electrical and Biomedical Engineering | Visiting student

Professor: Yoshinobu TATSUO

10/2015 – 09/2016 Tohoku University | Sendai (Japan)

Major: Aerospace Engineering | Exchange year

Professor: Tanjuro MAKIHARA

10/2012 – 09/2015 "Technische Universität Dortmund" | Dortmund

Major: Electrical Engineering and Information Technology | Bachelor of Science (2,0) Thesis: Optimization of the thermal response of a sensor diode using modeling and technological simulation

Advisor: Dr. Ing. Sven Ebschke

09/2004 – 06/2012 Immanuel-Kant-Gymnasium | Dortmund

Main Subjects: Math, Physics | Abitur (General university entrance qualification)

CERTIFICATES

 08/2023
 Meta Front-End Developer

 04/2023
 Codecademy: Full-Stack Engineer

 02/2023
 Integrata Cegos: C++ for Beginners

 09/2022
 Codecademy: iOS Developer Career Path

 08/2022
 Codecademy: Learn Intermediate Swift Course

08/2021 AlgoExpert: Certificate of Completion

ABILITIES AND KNOWLEDGE

Programming HTML / CSS / JavaScript, Swift, Python, C / C++, C#

 ${\sf Git\,/\,GitHub,\,TortoiseSVN,\,.net\,MAUI,\,Blazor,\,React,\,Redux,\,JEST,\,Node.js,\,Express.js,\,SQL,\,SQLite,\,SQLit$

PostgreSQL, RESTful API

Professional Advantest T2000 IPSE, Altium, Eagle, CANoe, CAPL, DOORS,

Language German, Russian: Native

English: C1/C2 Japanese: B2/C1

OTHER

Hobbies Sports (Running, Fitness, Soccer, Diving), Music (Piano), Programming